dnsbelgium.be 2018-09-03

# Privacy policy | DNS Belgium

### General

As manager of the .be, .brussels and .vlaanderen domain name extensions, DNS Belgium comes into possession of a number of personal data. This data has to be processed to manage the .be, .brussels and .vlaanderen domain names and related services. DNS Belgium is particularly careful with this data and processes it mainly in accordance with the services concerning domain name registration and management. 

We would hereby like to explain which data we process and why. We also want to inform you about your rights and where to go for your questions and/or complaints. 

### Contact data 

DNS Belgium receives a number of personal data directly and indirectly for which it serves as the controller. 

In addition, DNS Belgium has appointed a data protection officer. 

If you have questions about the processing of your personal data or your rights, you can always contact us. 

#### Data controller contact details

DNS Belgium vzw

Ubicenter, Philipssite 5, box 13

3001 Leuven

Tel. +32 16 284970

#### Data protection officer contact details 

DNS Belgium vzw

Attention: Peter Vergote

Ubicenter, Philipssite 5, box 13

3001 Leuven

### How does your personal data wind up in our possession? 

DNS Belgium processes the data of the following categories of persons: 

  * Registrants of a .be, .brussels or .vlaanderen domain name; 
  * Users/visitors of the website [www.dnsbelgium.be](http://www.dnsbelgium.be/) or other websites under the direct management of DNS Belgium; 
  * Persons who call on the services of DNS Belgium or come into contact with us through one of our communication channels; 
  * Persons who act as representatives of a party with which DNS Belgium works together under contract or in another way. 

The data of the registrants comes into the possession of DNS Belgium through the registrar to whom the party concerned turned to have the domain name registered. 

The data of other categories of persons is processed directly by DNS Belgium. 

### Which data is processed and why? 

For registrants of .be, .brussels and .vlaanderen domain names

For registrants of .be, .brussels and .vlaanderen domain names: surname, forename, address, e-mail address, telephone and fax numbers.

This data is processed exclusively under the operational activities of DNS Belgium as the technical manager of the .be, .brussels and .vlaanderen domain name zones and will not be commercially exploited by DNS Belgium.

DNS Belgium needs this data to perform correctly the agreement concluded through the registration of the domain name. DNS Belgium will therefore be able to inform you if there are (technical) problems with the domain name or if the general terms and conditions for the management of .be domain names are amended.

Processing is also necessary to defend the legitimate interests of third parties. DNS Belgium must therefore be able to share data with governmental institutions for the performance of their legal duties (e.g. criminal investigation). In addition, processing is also necessary in domain name disputes where data has to be communicated to dispute settling authorities (Cepani for .be domain names, WIPO (and other organizations appointed by ICANN) for .brussels/.vlaanderen domain names) or to legal or regulatory representatives of third parties who wish to assert certain rights relating to one or more specific domain names.

The processing in principle entails no transmission of personal data to countries or authorities outside the European Economic Area (EEA). If DNS Belgium should nonetheless receive requests for processing outside the EEA, DNS Belgium will make sure that appropriate guarantees are provided and that the registrant is informed accordingly before proceeding to such processing.

The aforementioned data is stored by DNS Belgium for an unspecified period. Contact details which have never been linked to an effective domain name registration are however deleted automatically after 6 months. Contact data which were linked to an effective domain name registration can be deleted at the request of the party concerned if the domain name was cancelled more than 10 years ago.

For users/visitors of www.dnsbelgium.be or other websites under direct management of DNS Belgium

For users/visitors of [www.dnsbelgium.be](http://www.dnsbelgium.be/) or other websites under direct management of DNS Belgium: IP address, cookies (data on the website visit such as language preference, number of pages viewed, which links were clicked, etc.). If you use online forms on our websites, the following personal data may be processed: surname, forename, address, e-mail address, telephone number.

This data is processed by DNS Belgium exclusively in order to optimize the use of its websites and services to the parties concerned. It will not be exploited by DNS Belgium for commercial purposes.

The processing of this data is necessary to defend the legitimate interests of DNS Belgium and more specifically to enable us to optimize our service and to make it easier to use and to navigate on our websites. The processing of this data is also required in certain cases (use of online forms) to counter abuse (spam, false declarations).

Data processed as a result of a simple visit to our websites may be transmitted to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA). DNS Belgium has nonetheless taken the necessary measures to ensure that this data is anonymized in such a situation so that the parties concerned cannot be identified by the recipient of said data. Data processed as a result of completing online forms is not transmitted to countries or authorities outside the EEA.

Data processed as a result of a simple visit to our sites is stored for 1 year and then deleted automatically. Data processed as a result of completing online forms is stored by DNS Belgium for an unspecified period. This data is stored in a Customer Relationship Management (CRM) application (more specifically, that of BPM Online, [www.bpmonline.com](http://www.bpmonline.com/)) which enables us to optimize our service. Processed personal data may be removed manually at the request of the party concerned if more than 12 months have lapsed since this data was stored.

For persons who call on the services of DNS Belgium or come into contact with us through one of our communication channels

For persons who call on the services of DNS Belgium or come into contact with us through one of our communication channels: surname, forename, e-mail address, telephone number.

This data is processed by DNS Belgium exclusively in order to optimize our service to the parties concerned. It will not be exploited by DNS Belgium for commercial purposes.

The processing of this data is necessary to defend the legitimate interests of DNS Belgium and more specifically to enable us to optimize our service by addressing more specifically the needs of persons who contact our services. The processing of the foregoing data entails no transmission of such personal data to countries or authorities outside the European Economic Area (EEA).

Where applicable (not simply upon telephone contacts) the processed data is stored by DNS Belgium for an unspecified period. This data is stored in a Customer Relationship Management (CRM) application (more specifically that of BPM Online, www.bpmonline.com) which enables us to optimize the service to the parties concerned. Processed personal data may be deleted manually at the request of the party concerned if more than 12 months have lapsed since this data was stored.

For persons who act as representatives of a party with which DNS Belgium works together under contract or in another way

For persons who act as representatives of a party with which DNS Belgium works together under contract or in another way: surname, forename, e-mail address, telephone number. 

This data are processed by DNS Belgium exclusively to optimize the cooperation with the persons concerned. It will not be exploited by DNS Belgium for commercial purposes. 

The processing of this data is necessary either in connection with the performance of an agreement or to defend the legitimate interests of DNS Belgium. More specifically, this processing enables DNS Belgium to work more smoothly with the aforementioned parties. 

The processing of the above data entails no transmission of these personal data to countries or authorities outside the European Economic Area (EEA). 

The processed data is stored by DNS Belgium for an unspecified period. This data is stored in a Customer Relationship Management (CRM) application to optimize the cooperation with contractual and other professional partners. Processed personal data may be removed manually at the request of the party concerned if more than 12 months have lapsed since the termination of the professional cooperation or as soon as the party concerned is no longer affiliated with the organization with which DNS Belgium cooperates. 

### Your rights

To make the new regulation on the protection of your privacy rights comprehensible, we would like to provide a summary of what you can expect from us. 

For the sake of convenience, the most important rights that you can invoke are summarized below. 

#### Right of access to your data processed by DNS Belgium 

If this is not sufficiently evident from our privacy policy, you can always ask us which of your data we process, why, to whom we provide it, and how long we store it. 

We may require specific identity details from you in order to answer your question properly. 

#### Right to rectification of your data processed by DNS Belgium 

It is obviously in both our interests for us to process only correct data. If you find that certain data is incorrect or incomplete, you are of course always welcome to inform us. We will supplement or correct your data as promptly as possible. 

A particular remark is in order for .be/.brussels/.vlaanderen registrants because we do not control this data directly. We only process it based on the input from the registrar who manages your domain name. 

You must report changes in your personal data to the registrar who manages your domain name. The registrant will adapt the data for you and make sure that these changes are entered also in the DNS Belgium database. This is the most logical approach because if you inform only DNS Belgium, you would have to inform the registrar as well at a later point. Otherwise, you run the risk that the registrar cannot contact you (to send the annual renewal invoice, for instance) and your domain name may be deleted inadvertently. 

#### Right to erasure (right to be forgotten)

DNS Belgium is the unique source that can provide a summary of the lifecycle of a domain name. In that respect, we would like to keep the registration history of a domain name intact. 

This does not of course preclude that DNS Belgium will consider every request to exercise the right to be forgotten and assess the feasibility thereof. 

Our privacy policy already stipulates a number of time periods during which we will store data. DNS Belgium is naturally prepared to delete data if it is ascertained that 1) the aforementioned time period has expired; and 2) if the data is no longer needed for the envisaged processing purposes. 

#### Right to restriction of processing 

DNS Belgium endeavours to keep the processing of personal data to a minimum. 

If you think the processing by us should be restricted further, please let us know. DNS Belgium will then examine as promptly as possible whether the conditions of Article 18 GDPR are met and whether or not further processing is appropriate. 

#### Right to data portability 

DNS Belgium is ready to help with administrative simplification and can above all provide .be/.brussels/.vlaanderen registrants with data that can prove useful for transferring to other authorities. 

In this specific context, we would like to point out that our .be registrants can download a certificate with the summery of the registrant data. For more information, go to: [www.dnsbelgium.be ](http://www.dnsbelgium.be/)

#### Right to object to data processing

DNS Belgium endeavours to keep the processing of personal data to a minimum.  

If you think that, on the basis of your specific situation, you can object to the processing of your data, feel free to inform DNS Belgium. 

The data protection officer will look into your specific situation in the light of the provisions of Article 21 GDPR and assess whether your objection to processing is justified. If the data protection officer’s assessment of your request is positive, DNS Belgium will cease immediately any further processing of your data. 

#### Automated individual decision-making, including profiling 

DNS Belgium takes no decision based on automated processing or profiling. 

#### Lodging a complaint with the competent authorities

If you think that your rights are violated or that DNS Belgium has failed in protecting your rights, you are free to lodge a complaint with the competent governmental authority responsible for the protection of your personal data (Data Protection Authority or DPA). 

In principle you must lodge your complaint with the authority of the EU member state in which you reside. 

For Belgium, the DPA is the Privacy Commission, 35 Drukpersstraat, 1000 Brussels, Tel. +32 2 2744800, [www.privacycommission.be ](http://www.privacycommission.be/) 

We would of course appreciate it if you contact us first to see whether a solution can be found to the problem you have encountered.  

### Additional announcements 

Data lookups through WHOIS

DNS Belgium offers a so-called WHOIS search function on its website www.dnsbelgium.be that can be used to obtain the contact details of a registrant by entering the specific domain name. 

DNS Belgium wishes to stress that the WHOIS function has been adapted to maximise the protection of privacy. 

First of all, a distinction is drawn between domain names registered in the name of private persons and those registered on the basis of legal entities. 

For domain names registered in the name of private persons, the data of the registrant are fully protected so nothing can be consulted via WHOIS. The same applies for any “onsite” and/or “tech” contacts linked to such domain names, provided this contact too concerns a private person. For linked contacts of the managing registrar, we cannot show the name of natural contact persons but we can show the contact details of the company. 

For domain name registrations in the name of legal entities, the data of the registrant is always shown via WHOIS, but with the exception of the name of natural contact persons. For linked “onsite,” “techn” and registrar contacts, the same rules apply as those mentioned above for private domain name registrations.  

Access to data for staff of DNS Belgium 

As already mentioned, the internal systems of DNS Belgium (e.g. the CRM application) sometimes contains personal data.

Pursuant to the principles concerning “privacy by design” and “privacy by default,” DNS Belgium has taken measures so that its staff have access to personal data only as and when required for the performance of their respective tasks in the organization. This prevents unnecessary exposure of personal data and the risk of data leaks is minimized further.

Technical security measures

In line with the mirroring of its management systems, DNS Belgium uses what are called “cloud” services. Accordingly, the cloud services of AWS (only EU sites) are called upon for hosting the registration platform. 

DNS Belgium has opted for a specific setup, whereby all data hosted at AWS is encrypted using the most recent cryptographic technologies. In the – very highly unlikely – eventuality of a serious incident at AWS, where data might be accessed by unauthorized persons, the data of DNS Belgium will still be illegible because of the applied encryption. Naturally, this once again leads to the further minimization of data leaks. 

Guarantees on non-commercial use of your data

DNS Belgium is not a commercial entity and will not exploit your data for commercial purposes. It will consequently not pass your data in bulk to third parties who are or are not business partners of DNS Belgium, even if the latter should explicitly so request. You therefore get a guarantee from us that your data will not be used for direct marketing, commercial e-mails or other forms of canvassing. 

DNS Belgium provides the data to third parties, exclusively on a selective case-by-case basis, in the following instances: 

  * At the request of a governmental authority (local or federal, judicial or administrative) for the performance of their legal duties; 
  * At the request of a dispute settlement institution as part of an alternative dispute resolution (ADR); 
  * At the request of an interested party, with the prior assessment by the legal department of DNS Belgium(see further). 

DNS Belgium does call on third parties for certain technical solutions such as AWS for cloud services. This means that data can be stored on locations other than the registered office of DNS Belgium. As already explained above, in such cases DNS Belgium takes the necessary precautions to secure adequate data protection (particularly through encryption) and to prevent unauthorized access. 

Requesting the contact details of a specific registrant 

If the registrant of a .be/.brussels/.vlaanderen domain name is a private person, his contact details may not be consulted via WHOIS. Those who wish to request these data, can complete the application form and submit it to the legal department of DNS Belgium. 

On this application form, the applicant has to: 

  * Mention and underpin the legitimate reasons for his request; 
  * Accept a waiver in which he undertakes not to use the requested personal data for purposes other than what is mentioned in the application form (and/or indicated in the appended documents); 
  * Provide his full name and address (including e-mail address, telephone and fax number, and in the case of a legal entity, the company number). 

The legal department of DNS Belgium will examine and assess each application thoroughly in the light of the requirements for special data processing. If the assessment is positive, the requested data will be provided to the applicant. 

### ICANN

The Internet Corporation for Assigned Names and Numbers, a non-profit organisation that is responsible worldwide for managing domain names.

### WHOIS

Look-up which gives information about the registrant of the domain name, his registrar, the name server and also some information about the domain status. 

### registrar

Is the entity that registers a domain name for a company, organization or person. Next to the “resale” of web addresses registrars can also offer hosting services, web design... 

### registrant

Domain owner, person who holds a domain name.

### SPAM

Collective term used for unwanted e-mail messages.

### Hosting

rent of a physical space to store a web server which is permanently connected to the internet. This service will typically be offered by your Internet Service Provider.

### DNS

Domain Name System or Domain Name Server. The global DNS is the system and protocol used on the internet to translate domain names into IP addresses and vice versa. 

### ADR

Alternative Dispute Resolution. Any party with an interest can lodge an application for the alternative dispute resolution with CEPINA to settle a dispute about a .be domain name. The dispute is assessed by an independent Third-Party Decision-Maker, who is a legal expert in the matter. The Third-Party Decider may decide to delete the domain name or to transfer the name to the complainant. Under normal circumstances, the registrant is able to reply once in writing to the complainant's arguments.
